# James (Jay) Jordan

Software Developer at EmployReward Solutions, Inc.

jamescyriljordan@gmail.com

# Summary

I have been developing software for over 10 years. I developed a passion for it when I was in my teenage years, and over the next 15 years I have, in one form or another, developed websites and web applications continuously. I began developing websites for family, friends, and eventually evolved into commercial software development. I am currently employed as software developer, and I spend about 10 hours a day completely immersed. My goal is to take the knowledge that I have acquired and use it to create a software development firm that will be the benchmark for software companies of the future.

# Experience

# Software Developer at EmployReward Solutions, Inc.

October 2012 - Present (2 years 2 months)

Design, innovate, and improve existing software. Create and consult on new software. Work with asp.net (C# and VB), javascript(jquery/ajax/json), html, css, sql/t-sql, ect to provide top quality software solutions for business development.

3 recommendations available upon request

#### Founder at Innovation Nexus

January 2012 - Present (2 years 11 months)

Serving as chief executive of Innovation Nexus and, in partnership with the Board, I'm responsible for the success of Innovation Nexus. Together, the Board and I assure Innovation Nexus's relevance to the community, the accomplishment of Innovation Nexus's mission and vision, and the accountability of Innovation Nexus to its diverse constituents.

The Board delegates responsibility for management and day-to-day operations to me, and I have the authority to carry out these responsibilities, in accordance with the direction and policies established by the Board. I provide direction and enabling to the Board as it carries out its governance functions.

1 recommendation available upon request

## IT Consultant at Card Payment Solutions

October 2011 - October 2012 (1 year 1 month)

Was responsible for company network, hardware, and software. I provided consultation on best practices for IT related issues, as well as handling the technical side of installing ATM's, training technicians on installation, and customers on use.

2 recommendations available upon request

#### IT Technician at Florence-Darlington Technical College

August 2009 - May 2011 (1 year 10 months)

#### **Independent Contractor at Hospice Care of South Carolina**

2009 - 2011 (2 years)

## Certifications

## JavaScript and AJAX

lynda.com License 572A75 April 2014

## **Heartbleed Tactics for Small IT Shops**

lynda.com License 176FC8 April 2014

#### **ASP.NET Essential Training**

lynda.com License 57634E March 2014

#### A+ Certified

CompTIA License SDHQKYR2YDF129SK October 2011 to October 2014

#### **C# Essential Training**

lynda.com License F88744 April 2014

#### Foundations of Programming: Object-Oriented Design

lynda.com License 5B4890 April 2014

## **Foundations of Programming: Fundamentals**

lynda.com License 9A3482 April 2014

#### **SQL Essential Training (2009)**

lynda.com License B2033D April 2014

#### **ASP.NET MVC 4 Essential Training**

lynda.com License 6B9C06 May 2014

#### **jQuery Essential Training**

lynda.com License 97FF02 June 2014

#### jQuery Data with AJAX

lynda.com License FF96EF June 2014

#### **AJAX Crash Course by SitePoint**

lynda.com License 952BCF June 2014

#### **Agile Project Management**

lynda.com License F5F72B June 2014

# **JavaScript Essential Training**

lynda.com License 85479F July 2014

# Skills & Expertise

**ASP.NET MVC** 

**ASP.NET** 

**C**#

**VB.NET** 

**A+ Certified** 

**SQL Server Management Studio** 

**SQL** 

**jQuery** 

**JavaScript** 

**PHP** 

**AJAX** 

Cisco IOS

**Computer Security** 

Windows 7

Laptops

XP

**System Administration** 

**Windows Server** 

Windows XP

**Computer Hardware** 

**Technical Support** 

**Software Installation** 

**Printers** 

**DHCP** 

TCP/IP

**DNS** 

**Network Administration** 

**Microsoft Office** 

**Troubleshooting** 

**Operating Systems** 

**Routers** 

**Cabling** 

**System Deployment** 

**Desktop Support** 

Windows

Hardware

**HTML** 

**Deployment** 

**Problem Solving** 

**Firewalls** 

Windows Server 2008

**CIW** 

Microsoft SQL Server

**CSS** 

**Web Development** 

**Software Development** 

Customer Service Management Leadership Training

# Education

## **Western Governors University**

Bachelor of Science (B.S.) Information Technology - Software, Computer Software Development, 2012 - 2015

## Florence-Darlington Technical College

Associates, Telecommunications Management (Computer It/Networking), 2008 - 2011

Activities and Societies: Work-Study

**Private Tutoring** 

# **Interests**

Web Design, Programming, Software Development, Golf, Exercise

# **Projects**

### CodeFlo

August 2014 to Present

Members:James (Jay) Jordan

Initiative by the North Dargan Innovation Center of Florence SC to teach web programming and design skills to the community.

# James (Jay) Jordan

Software Developer at EmployReward Solutions, Inc.

jamescyriljordan@gmail.com



# 9 people have recommended James (Jay)

"Jay is an extremely versatile and committed software developer. There are few that can learn new software development techniques and incorporate them into their development as quickly as Mr. Jordan. He continually proves his dedication to truly understanding and delivering solutions to meet business needs and requirements."

— **Jeremy Henry**, *Director of Information Systems*, *EmployReward Solutions*, *Inc.*, managed James (Jay) at EmployReward Solutions, Inc.

"Jay is a results-driven IT Professional with a passion for delivering exceptional service to his employer and clients. I have had the pleasure of working with Jay for a little over a year at this time and he has been instrumental in assisting in upgrading our web presence while also providing innovative solutions to improving our internal processes and creating a more streamlined and user-friendly system for case management. Jay can be credited with helping bring success to the Call Center at EmployReward Solutions and the company at large."

— **Tripp Carter**, *Senior Career Coach*, *EmployReward Solutions*, *Inc.*, worked with James (Jay) at EmployReward Solutions, Inc.

"Jay delivers excellence in his work. He has a thorough understanding of software development and is an integral part of the IT department at EmployReward Solutions, Inc. His diligence is also matched with professional character and keen sense in problem resolution."

— **William Preston**, *Career Coach*, *EmployReward Solutions*, *Inc.*, worked with James (Jay) at EmployReward Solutions, Inc.

"Jay Jordan provides excellent customer service with his attention to detail, his professionalism and his determination to provide a job well done. It is very obvious to me that solving his clients specific problems and meeting their needs is of utmost importance to him. His approach is not "boilerplate", but customized to each individual client. You can count on Jay to get the job done, whatever it may be."

# - shelby jenerette, was James (Jay)'s client

"Jay is the most professional, experienced, friendly and knowledgeable person I have ever had the experience to work with. His knowledge and experience in software development, web design, networking and troubleshooting would lead me to recommend him to anyone who is looking for only the best in those fields."

— Travis Anderson Travis, Director Of Operations, Card Payment Solutions, worked directly with James (Jay) at Card Payment Solutions

"James (Jay) was an excellent resource for CPS. His expertise, ability to think on his feet, and problem solving skills were valuable to the work environment. He treated both customers and co-workers with patience, dignity and respect. James (Jay) is never satisfied with mediocre but strives for the best, He demonstrated a capacity and eagerness to learn and challenged himself to be a positive contributor to the team effort."

— **Linda Harmsen**, *Exec. Assistant, Card Payment Solutions LLC*, managed James (Jay) indirectly at Card Payment Solutions

"James has always been someone that was capable of thinking far outside the box, bringing unique and incredible solutions to the table when facing highly complex problems. His ability to multitask and prioritize would make him a valuable asset to any company lucky enough to hire him."

— Casey Cockfield, Information Technology Specialist, Florence-Darlington Technical College, managed James (Jay) at Florence-Darlington Technical College

"Jay was already working in the IT department when I was first hired. I learned many things working with him that has really helped me out in my job today. There was not too much that he could not do within our department, as well as his side projects that he had going on. Jay was quick to take charge of a project and see it through with perfection. I would not hesitate to add Jay to my team if I were ever given the chance. His customer service skills are phenomenal and he is a great leader."

— **Trey Rogers**, *IT Support*, *Florence-Darlington Technical College*, worked directly with James (Jay) at Florence-Darlington Technical College

"James is a great worker. Many of the large deployments we undertook directly involved him. James has a great working personality and was very capable of handling any delegated tasks. Even while pursuing his Associates he concentrated on learning other non-degree related programming skills. He has always maintained a very positive attitude and focused on future beneficial plans/business opportunities."

— William O'neil Broach, Academic IT Support Technician, Florence Darlington Technical College, managed James (Jay) indirectly at Florence-Darlington Technical College

Contact James (Jay) on LinkedIn